<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Travel &#8211; BD Blogs</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>best wordpress blog site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 05:20:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/12/cropped-android-chrome-512x512-2-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Travel &#8211; BD Blogs</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Sylhet Tea Garden: The Most Beautiful Tea Gardens in Bangladesh to visit </title>
		<link>./../../../sylhet-tea-garden/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../sylhet-tea-garden/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[khayrul]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 05:20:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sylhet Tea Garden]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=2064</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sylhet Tea Garden Tea Estate is the most beautiful and oldest tea garden in Bangladesh. The tea state is located in Amberkhana point of Sylhet near the airport.Lakkatura tea estate is the largest tea garden in Bangladesh. 1.5km forward towards the Osmani Airport in Chaukidhenki Upazila of Sylhet district. Sylhet Tea Garden covers 1293 hectares [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Sylhet Tea Garden Tea Estate is the most beautiful and oldest tea garden in Bangladesh. The tea state is located in Amberkhana point of Sylhet near the airport.<br>Lakkatura tea estate is the largest tea garden in Bangladesh.  1.5km forward towards the Osmani Airport in Chaukidhenki Upazila of Sylhet district. Sylhet Tea Garden covers 1293 hectares or about 3200 acres. The garden produced about 500,000 kg of tea every year.  signboard is seen towards the airport. The garden manager and assistant manager’s bungalow are on the top of the hill.<br>Sylhet Tea Garden in the guesthouse of the garden which is located inside the Lakkatura tea garden. There are three rooms, kitchens and guestrooms. Guests can do Barbecue and Campfire. Hotels are also available in the city. So one can also stay in hotels.  visitors want to just walk in the garden, they can go inside the main gate asking the guard to go inside.<br> by public CNG to visit Lakkatura tea garden from Amberkhana point of Sylhet and the rent will be Tk 5-10, and 15-20 tk in rickshaw. It will take 10 mins.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="630" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/12/sylhet_tea_garden1-1024x630.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2065"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Sylhet Tea Garden</figcaption></figure>



<p><a href="https://www.mediabangladesh.net/tea-gardens-bangladesh/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sylhet Tea Garden OF BANGLADESH</a>, is renowned for the beauty of its tea gardens, and among the lot, Lakkatura is considered the most scenic. It is also one of the largest tea gardens in the country, covering a total of 3,200 acres. This estate was officially established in 1875, and it now produces an astounding 550 tons of tea each year. </p>



<p>A number of dirt roads intersect the garden, some purpose-built to transport sylhet Tea Garden across and beyond the grounds. Others are simply part of a larger network of roads cutting through Lakkatura, taking visitors through hills of neatly manicured rows of tea plants. Following the latter set of roads takes you to several rural villages in and around Lakkatura estate, including makeshift villages where migrant workers live during the harvest.</p>



<p>The British East India Company first introduced tea cultivation in Bangladesh in 1840, but it was only in 1857 that tea became a commercial occupation. In 2012, Bangladesh produced more than 70,000 tons of tea. Sylhet Tea Garden of its small size, the South Asian country is the 12th-largest tea producer in the world, employing more than 300,000 people. The industry is supervised by the Bangladesh Tea Board and the Bangladesh Tea Research Institute.</p>


<h3 id="sylhet-tea-garden-you-know-before-to-go">Sylhet Tea Garden You Know Before To Go</h3>


<p>Sylhet Tea Garden is a few minutes from the center of Sylhet. The easiest way to get to the estate is by CNG (a kind of autorickshaw used all over Bangladesh). Upon arrival at Lakkatura, you can either report to the main office, where you can hire a guide or listen to a lecture about the sylhet Tea Garden you can wander around the garden by yourself. It is not rare to come across newlyweds having their wedding pictures taken at the picturesque tea garden.</p>



<div class="is-layout-flex wp-container-3 wp-block-columns">
<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/12/sylhet_tea_garden3.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-2066" width="426" height="223"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">sylhet tea garden</figcaption></figure>
</div>



<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/12/sylhet_tea_garden2.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2067" width="425" height="283"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Syhet tea garden</figcaption></figure>
</div>
</div>


<h3 id="beauti-of-sylhet-tea-garden">Beauti Of Sylhet Tea Garden:</h3>


<p><ul style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; font-family: &quot;Open Sans&quot;, Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; text-align: justify; white-space: normal;"><li style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">venenatis orci vel sollicitudin semper.</li><li style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">Morbi vestibulum eros eget ex commodo, vitae aliquet odio vulputate.</li><li style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">In id orci non neque bibendum volutpat.</li><li style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">Nullam a lacus tempus, porttitor enim ullamcorper, scelerisque lacus.</li><li style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">Pellentesque vulputate nisi sed sem scelerisque commodo.</li><li style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">Pellentesque vel nulla cursus, fringilla felis id, aliquam arcu.</li></ul></p>



<p>Sylhet Tea Garden in the guesthouse of the garden which is located inside the Lakkatura tea garden. There are three rooms, kitchens and guestrooms. Guests can do Barbecue and Campfire. Hotels are also available in the city. So one can also stay in hotels. visitors want to just walk in the garden, they can go inside the main gate asking the guard to go inside.<br>Sylhet Tea Garden by public CNG to visit Lakkatura tea garden from Amberkhana point of Sylhet and the rent will be Tk 5-10, and 15-20 tk in rickshaw. It will take 10 mins.</p>



<p>If you Read about Jaflong . <a href="./../../../jaflong-turiest/index.html">Let&#8217;s Go&#8230;</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../sylhet-tea-garden/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jaflong: Beauti Of Nature In Bangladesh</title>
		<link>./../../../jaflong-turiest/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../jaflong-turiest/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[khayrul]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 04:55:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jaflong]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=2058</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jaflong like fog on the mountain, for the first time, you may not realize. It is so tough to turn your eyes watching the combination of the mountain with the cloud under the blue sky. White Cloud, Blue Sky, High Mountains, Blue Water, what a beautiful sight! Jaflong is such a place like this. We all know, Sylhet is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Jaflong</strong> like fog on the mountain, for the first time, you may not realize. It is so tough to turn your eyes watching the combination of the mountain with the cloud under the blue sky. White Cloud, Blue Sky, High Mountains, Blue Water, what a beautiful sight! <strong>Jaflong</strong> is such a place like this. We all know, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sylhet" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sylhet</a> is a beautiful place in Bangladesh and Jaflong is one of them.</p>



<p>Jaflong is located in Gowainghat Upazila of Sylhet district of Bangladesh, 62 kilometers north-east of Sylhet city, on the foothills of the Khasia-Jaintia hill along India’s Meghalaya border. On the opposite side, it is Khasia Jaintia hill, and in this side the river on the east. The fountain is going on in the hills, and the pebbles of various colored stones on the level of the river. If you look from the distance, it will seem the mountains are standing reclining with the sky. <strong><a href="https://www.travelmate.com.bd/jaflong-travel-guideline/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jaflong</a></strong> the white clouds are flying touching the mountains. Where else can this kind of beauty be found, except Jaflong?</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="806" height="372" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/12/jaflong1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-2059"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Jaflong Turiest Sports</figcaption></figure>



<p>Jaflong, known as the&nbsp;<em>daughter of nature</em>, is familiar all over the country.&nbsp;<a href="http://en.banglapedia.org/index.php?title=Piyain_River" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Piyain River</a>&nbsp;that is piled with the stone will amaze you. The sight of the fountain from Dawki and Khasia Mountains Of India, Dawki Bridge, and the clear water attracts the visitors. If you come to Sylhet and do not visit Jaflong, the traveling of you would seem unfulfilled.</p>



<p>Considering the season, Winter or Monsoon, it varies the beauty. In the rainy season, the beauty of Jaflong goes in the different levels. The atmosphere becomes transparent and the environment is clear. The transparent water, the fountain from the mountains and calm environment takes your feeling in another stage.</p>



<p>The clear stream of water from the Piyin river flowing over the rocks, the hanging Dauki Bridge, and the white cloud game in the high mountains have made Jaflong unique.</p>



<p>It is an amazing natural place on the earth combined with hills, forests, rivers, blue sky, endless green tea garden,&nbsp;and lots of waterfalls.</p>



<p>In each season, Sylhet, and Jaflong reveal a similar form that keeps tourists interested in traveling throughout the year. Jaflong is a really natural beauty of Bangladesh. Visit Jaglong with your family and friends to spend a quality vacation.</p>



<p>The clear stream of water from the Piyin river flowing over the rocks, the hanging Dauki Bridge, and the white cloud game in the high mountains have made Jaflong unique.</p>



<p>It is an amazing natural place on the earth combined with hills, forests, rivers, blue sky, endless green tea garden,&nbsp;and lots of waterfalls.</p>



<p>In each season, Sylhet, and Jaflong reveal a similar form that keeps tourists interested in traveling throughout the year. Jaflong is a really&nbsp;natural beauty&nbsp;of Bangladesh. Visit Jaglong with your family and friends to spend a quality vacation.</p>


<h3 id="jaflong-travel-gidline">Jaflong Travel Gidline:</h3>


<p>Jaflong is lovely piece of heaven is situated just below the mountain range where hills are greenish with the forests and blue sky melt in the river’s water.</p>



<p>The clear stream of water from the Piyin river flowing over the rocks, the hanging Dauki Bridge, and the white cloud game in the high mountains have made Jaflong unique.</p>



<p>It is an amazing natural place on the earth combined with hills, forests, rivers, blue sky, endless green tea garden,&nbsp;and lots of waterfalls.</p>



<p>In each season, Sylhet, and Jaflong reveal a similar form that keeps tourists interested in traveling throughout the year. Jaflong is a really natural beauty of Bangladesh. Visit Jaglong with your family and friends to spend a quality vacation.</p>



<div class="is-layout-flex wp-container-6 wp-block-columns">
<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="950" height="520" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/12/jaflong2.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-2060"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">jaflong sport</figcaption></figure>
</div>



<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="768" height="432" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/12/jaflong.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2061"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">jaflong sport</figcaption></figure>
</div>
</div>



<p><strong>Table of Contents</strong></p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://travelvibe.net/jaflong-travel-guide/#visit-jaflong-best-things-to-do-in-jaflong" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Jaflong: Best Things To Do In Jaflong</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://travelvibe.net/jaflong-travel-guide/#go-to-zero-point" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Go To Zero Point</a></li>



<li><a href="https://travelvibe.net/jaflong-travel-guide/#enjoy-the-scenic-beauty-in-sengram-punji-waterfalls" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Enjoy the scenic beauty in Sengram Punji Waterfalls</a></li>



<li><a href="https://travelvibe.net/jaflong-travel-guide/#witness-the-natural-beauty-of-piain-river" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Witness the natural beauty of Piain River</a></li>



<li><a href="https://travelvibe.net/jaflong-travel-guide/#meet-new-cultural-people-at-sengram-punji-khasia-village" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Meet new cultural people at Sengram Punji Khasia Village</a></li>



<li><a href="https://travelvibe.net/jaflong-travel-guide/#see-the-largest-stone-collection-activities" target="_blank" rel="noopener">See the largest Stone collection activities</a></li>



<li><a href="https://travelvibe.net/jaflong-travel-guide/#take-amazing-photos-at-jaflong-bridge" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Take amazing photos at Jaflong Bridge</a></li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><a href="https://travelvibe.net/jaflong-travel-guide/#how-to-go-to-jaflong" target="_blank" rel="noopener">How to go to Jaflong</a></li>



<li><a href="https://travelvibe.net/jaflong-travel-guide/#how-to-go-from-dhaka-to-sylhet-jaflong" target="_blank" rel="noopener">How to go from Dhaka to Sylhet, Jaflong</a></li>



<li><a href="https://travelvibe.net/jaflong-travel-guide/#how-to-go-from-chittagong-to-sylhet-to-reach-jaflong" target="_blank" rel="noopener">How to go from Chittagong to Sylhet to reach Jaflong</a></li>



<li><a href="https://travelvibe.net/jaflong-travel-guide/#how-to-go-from-sylhet-to-jaflong" target="_blank" rel="noopener">How to go from Sylhet to Jaflong</a></li>



<li><a href="https://travelvibe.net/jaflong-travel-guide/#where-to-stay-in-jaflong" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Where to stay in Jaflong</a></li>
</ul>



<p>Read more about<a href="./../index.html"> Lakkatura</a> Tea Garden Sylhet.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../jaflong-turiest/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
